LYSANDRO CARIOCA BRAGA

Montreal, QC, Canada Mobile: +1 (438) 466-8370 Email: lysandroc@gmail.com

Software engineer with ten years of experience developing and scaling applications. Outstanding problem solver with an aptitude for troubleshooting and the ability to quickly master new skill technology.

Programming Skills

- Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Golang, and SQL
- Technologies: React, Jest, NodeJS, GraphQL, AWS, Kubernetes, RabbitMQ, CouchDB and MongoDB

EXPERIENCE

• Stay22

Senior Software Engineer

Nov. 2021 - Present

• Map and Hub: Developing the next map generation at Stay 22. The backend stack has Typescript, Nodeis, MongoDB and Go. In the Frontend we use Typescript, React, Vue, MapLibre and Styled Components. I also maintain internal common libraries shared between our internal products.

• SysMap Solutions Software

Senior Software Engineer

Feb. 2021 - Nov. 2021

• Global Relationship Platform: A new product for Natura&Co to keep tracking of the beauty consultant relationship time in several countries. Implemented an event-driven design architecture to scale asynchronous relationship timing using AWS Lambda, SQS, NodeJS, and Scylla DB. Added new features ReactJS/Nodejs application. I've used Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Grafana and Kibana as a part of the devops process to scale and monitor the application.

• Instituto Atlântico

Senior Software Engineer

Apr. 2020 - Feb. 2021

• 3D Printer Dashboard: Developed a system a as service for HP that shows all information about 3D printer usage. Implemented a thin REST layer written in Golang that reads information from the AWS Redshift; Created dashboards from Figma using React, React Hooks, Typescript; Contributed to the internal DevOps organization creating yaml template steps used across multiple teams.

• OSF Digital

Senior Software Developer

May 2019 - Apr. 2020

• Private Pension: A solution that offers a private pension fund to customers. Developed a web application from scratch using ReactJS, React Hooks, Context API, RTL, and Styled Components from Sketch UI; Code was covered by 85% of unit testing; Led a team of three developers to build an end to end testing project using the cypress framework.

• Empreendimentos Pague Menos

Fortaleza, CE

Senior Software Developer, Tech Lead

Fev. 2014 - Apr. 2019

• Warehouse Order Picking System: A distributed system and data over CouchDB used to check and validate the picking process using the pick box method. Implemented a sample method algorithm to pick random boxes and reduce issues using Javascript; Optimized routines to clean up the local database on hundreds of workstations using NodeJS; Optimized the picking process from 2 hours to 5 minutes grouping them by transport routes.

EDUCATION

• Universidade Estadual do Ceara

Fortaleza, CE

Fortaleza, CE

Postgraduate Diploma in Software Engineering

May. 2017 - Feb. 2019

• Technologies in Systems Analysis and Development

Faculdade de Tecnologia Lourenço Filho

Jan. 2012 - Oct. 2014

• Professional Technical High School Education

Maranguape, CE Mar. 2009 - Dec. 2011

Escola Estadual de Educação Profissional Santa Rita